<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><qti-assessment-item xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imsqtiasi_v3p0" identifier="g5dry-g5-info-beavers-01-mcq" title="As it is used in paragraph 2, what does the word 'recharge' most nearly mean?" adaptive="false" time-dependent="false"><qti-response-declaration identifier="RESPONSE" cardinality="single" base-type="identifier"><qti-correct-response><qti-value>a</qti-value></qti-correct-response></qti-response-declaration><qti-outcome-declaration identifier="SCORE" cardinality="single" base-type="float"><qti-default-value><qti-value>0</qti-value></qti-default-value></qti-outcome-declaration><qti-outcome-declaration identifier="FEEDBACK" cardinality="single" base-type="identifier"/><qti-item-body><p>For a long time, ranchers in the high valleys of the western mountains saw the beaver as a nuisance. The animal felled young trees, flooded low pastures, and clogged the narrow streams that fed the cattle troughs. When the beavers were trapped out of a valley, the ranchers expected the land to improve. Instead, something they had not predicted began to happen, and it took scientists many years to understand why.</p><p>A beaver builds its dam not for shelter but to create a deep, calm pond in front of its lodge. To raise the water, the beaver drags branches and packs them with mud across a moving stream. This wall slows the current. Behind the dam, the water spreads sideways into the soil rather than rushing downhill. Engineers who study rivers call this stored water a recharge, because the wetland slowly refills the underground supply that feeds the valley through the dry months.</p><p>When the beavers vanished, the dams they had maintained fell apart within a few seasons. With nothing to slow it, the spring snowmelt tore straight down the channel in a single fast surge. The water that once lingered for months now left the valley in a matter of days. By midsummer the streams the ranchers depended on had dropped to a trickle, and the meadows that had stayed green well into August turned brown and brittle.</p><p>The loss reached beyond the water itself. The beaver ponds had been crowded with life. Frogs laid their eggs in the still shallows, and the trout that ranchers liked to fish for had sheltered in the cool, deep water behind the dams. Birds had nested in the willows that thrive only where the soil stays wet. As the ponds drained, this web of living things thinned and, in some valleys, disappeared entirely.</p><p>Decades later, a few researchers proposed an idea that sounded backward to many ranchers: bring the beavers back on purpose. In several valleys, teams trapped beavers from crowded streams and carried them to the dry, damaged channels. The work was slow and uncertain, and not every release took hold. Yet where the animals stayed and built, the change was unmistakable. First the new dams rose and the ponds returned. Next the willows greened along the banks and the soil grew spongy underfoot. Then the frogs and birds came back to the water. Finally, and most important to the ranchers, the streams ran cool and steady again through the heat of late summer.</p><p>The lesson the scientists drew was not really about beavers alone. It was about the hidden links inside a living landscape. A single animal, dismissed as a pest, turned out to hold the whole valley's water in place. Remove it, and the damage spread in directions no one had thought to watch. The beaver, it turned out, had been working as an engineer all along, building the very wetland the ranchers needed most.</p><qti-choice-interaction response-identifier="RESPONSE" max-choices="1" shuffle="true"><qti-prompt>As it is used in paragraph 2, what does the word 'recharge' most nearly mean?</qti-prompt><qti-simple-choice identifier="a">A refilling of the water held under the ground.</qti-simple-choice><qti-simple-choice identifier="b">A sudden burst of stored electrical power.</qti-simple-choice><qti-simple-choice identifier="c">A second attempt made after an earlier failure.</qti-simple-choice><qti-simple-choice identifier="d">A fee that is paid again for the same service.</qti-simple-choice></qti-choice-interaction></qti-item-body><qti-response-processing><qti-response-condition><qti-response-if><qti-match><qti-variable identifier="RESPONSE"/><qti-correct identifier="RESPONSE"/></qti-match><qti-set-outcome-value identifier="SCORE"><qti-base-value base-type="float">1</qti-base-value></qti-set-outcome-value><qti-set-outcome-value identifier="FEEDBACK"><qti-base-value base-type="identifier">CORRECT</qti-base-value></qti-set-outcome-value></qti-response-if><qti-response-else><qti-set-outcome-value identifier="SCORE"><qti-base-value base-type="float">0</qti-base-value></qti-set-outcome-value><qti-set-outcome-value identifier="FEEDBACK"><qti-base-value base-type="identifier">INCORRECT</qti-base-value></qti-set-outcome-value></qti-response-else></qti-response-condition></qti-response-processing><qti-modal-feedback outcome-identifier="FEEDBACK" identifier="CORRECT" show-hide="show"><qti-content-body><p>The passage defines the term in context: the wetland 'slowly refills the underground supply that feeds the valley,' so 'recharge' here means refilling the groundwater (a). Options b and d are common everyday senses of the word that the passage does not use.</p></qti-content-body></qti-modal-feedback><qti-modal-feedback outcome-identifier="FEEDBACK" identifier="INCORRECT" show-hide="show"><qti-content-body><p>Not quite. Reread the passage and find the exact words that answer the question.</p></qti-content-body></qti-modal-feedback></qti-assessment-item>